<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The arguments of the Right Honourable the Earl of Danby the second time, at the Court of King's Bench at Westminster, upon his lordship's motion for bail, the 29th day of June, term. Trin. 1682</title>
            <author>Leeds, Thomas Osborne, Duke of, 1631-1712, defendant.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1682</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 40 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A49986</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L922</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R11803</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12591272</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12591272</idno>
            <idno type="VID">63948</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A49986)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 63948)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 672:17)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The arguments of the Right Honourable the Earl of Danby the second time, at the Court of King's Bench at Westminster, upon his lordship's motion for bail, the 29th day of June, term. Trin. 1682</title>
                  <author>Leeds, Thomas Osborne, Duke of, 1631-1712, defendant.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 15 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Richard Tonson ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1682.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Leeds, Thomas Osborne, --  Duke of, 1631-1712.</term>
               <term>England and Wales. --  Court of King's Bench.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:63948:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THE ARGUMENTS OF THE RIGHT HONOURABLE THE EARL of DANBY The Second Time, At the COURT of KING'S-BENCH AT WESTMINSTER, Upon his Lordſhip's Motion for BAIL, The 29th. day of <hi>June,</hi> Term. <hi>Trin.</hi> 1682.</p>
            <p>As they were then Exactly taken.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Richard Tonſon</hi> within <hi>Grayes-Inn</hi> Gate next <hi>Grayes-Inn</hi> Lane, 1682.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:63948:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:63948:2"/>
            <head>THE Earl of Danby's ARGUMENTS At the Court of KING'S-BENCH, Upon his Lordſhips Motion for BAIL, The 29th Day of <hi>June, Term. Trin.</hi> 1682, &amp;c.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>The Right Honourable the Earl of</hi> Danby, <hi>appearing in the Court of</hi> Kings-Bench, <hi>the</hi> 29th <hi>Day of</hi> June, <hi>up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on his Writ of</hi> Habeas Corpus; <hi>the Return of the Writ was read by the Clerk of the Crown, and then his Lordſhips Councel Moved the Court, That the Return might be Filed, and his Lordſhip might be Enlarged from his Impriſonment upon Bail, his Lordſhip having very good and ſufficient Bail ready in Court; and thereupon the Earl applying himſelf to the Lord Chief-Juſtice, ſpoke to this Effect,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>EArl of</hi> Danby, My Lord, When I laſt attended your Lordſhips, and this Court, the Judges (or moſt of them) were of opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion, That what I then ſaid to your Lordſhip might deſerve further Conſideration; and therefore my Lord, I doubt not, but that your Lordſhip has been pleaſed to conſider further thereof.</p>
            <p>At that time, my Lord, none of the Judges but your Lordſhip, I think, made any very particular Objections againſt my being Bailed; and if I am able to offer any thing to your Lordſhip that may give a ſufficient Anſwer to thoſe Objections, I do not doubt but that your Lordſhip is ſo juſt, that you will not adhere to any Opinion, only be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe you have been once of that Opinion, if any thing can be ſhewed to convince you to change it. In confidence therefore, that I am before a Court which is not to be Influenced by any Body <hi>(how great ſoever,)</hi> nor by any thing but by the Laws of <hi>England,</hi> and by your Oaths to do Juſtice according to thoſe Laws; and being well aſſured of the
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:63948:3"/>Care which your Lordſhip will always have to maintain the <hi>Engliſh Liberties,</hi> with which your Lordſhip is Intruſted by the King, and by the Laws, and Inveſted with Power enough by both to defend them at all times, and againſt all Opinions whatſoever. My Lord, I ſay, pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuming, and not doubting of all this, I ſhall take upon me to add ſomething to what I have ſaid already to the Objections which were then made by your Lordſhip, and I hope I ſhall have liberty to Anſwer any new Objections that may be now made.</p>
            <p>My Lord, I take it for granted in the firſt place, That the Order of the Houſe of Lords is no Objection againſt my Bail, becauſe your Lordſhip was pleaſed to tell me ſo the laſt time I was here; and then I do reckon that thoſe Objections which have been made againſt my be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Bailed, may be ſummed up under theſe Three Heads.</p>
            <p>The Firſt, My Lord, as well as my memory will ſerve me, was, That as it was Incongruous for a Court which was Inferiour to this, to Bail any Man that was Committed by this Court, or to call in queſtion the Proceſs of this Court; ſo it would likewiſe be for this Court to do in my Caſe; for that if a Man were Committed by this Court, no Infe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rior Court could Bail that Man, (in Caſe His Majeſty ſhould think fit to Adjourn this Court from time to time) until this Court ſhould ſit again.</p>
            <p>The Second Objection was, That I am not Indefinitely Impriſoned, for that when His Majeſty ſhall pleaſe to call a Parliament, I would have Remedy; and therefore I muſt wait till His Majeſty ſhould pleaſe to call a Parliament.</p>
            <p>The Third was, That this Cauſe of mine was depending in a Superi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>or Court, which was too big for this Court, and that the Supreme Court having laid its hands upon me, therefore this Court could not Intermedle in that matter; my Lord, theſe to the beſt of my Remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brance, are the Subſtance of the Objections then made.</p>
            <p>The firſt of theſe, I have been told without doors, is taken to be one of the weightieſt Objections againſt me, and truly I ſhould be very glad it ſhould prove ſo, becauſe I think it may be ſo eaſily Anſwered.</p>
            <p>For in the firſt place, As to the calling in queſtion the Proceſs, I conceive that Bail is no calling in queſtion any Proceſs, and this Court did ſurely think ſo, when in the Caſe of the Earl of <hi>Shaftsbury,</hi> they did declare, That had he not come to them in the time of an Adjourn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Parliament, they would have Bailed him; and my Lord, as nothing is more evident, then that this Court and other Courts do meddle with the Proceedings of that Superior Court, ſo I do not doubt but to make appear, that they do meddle in a much greater degree then what I deſire of Bail; and that the Conſequences of what they do, eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Day practice, may be far more dangerous to the Subject, then the Bailing of me can be.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:63948:3"/>
            <p>For that part of the Objection that compares a Commitment of this Court, to a Commitment of the Houſe of Lords, and doth from thence conclude, that becauſe an Inferiour Court to this cannot Bail a Man who is Committed by this Court, therefore this Court cannot Bail a Man who is Committed by a Superior Court.</p>
            <p>This ſeems ſo very unequal a Compariſon, and the inequality of it ſo obvious, that truly I thought it had not needed any Anſwer; for I would deſire no other Anſwer from your Lordſhip, (if you can give it me,) then what an Inferior Court may give to any Perſon that ſhall come before them with the like Requeſt: For they may give him good and ſufficient Reaſons why they do not Bail him; they may not only tell the Party that he is Committed by the Superior Court of the the <hi>Kings-Bench,</hi> and that he muſt go thither for his Relief; but they can give him good Reaſons why he muſt do ſo; for they can tell him that the Court of <hi>Kings-Bench</hi> will ſit next <hi>Term,</hi> they can tell him when that <hi>Term</hi> will begin, and they can tell him how long that <hi>Term</hi> will laſt, and they can tell him that the Court of <hi>Kings-Bench</hi> cannot be Diſſolved as the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament may be: And my Lord, this takes away all that Priſoners pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tences, to ſay that he is an Indefinite Priſoner, and if your Lordſhip can give me any ſuch Anſwers as theſe, I ſhall be as well ſatisfied as that Man ought to be; but if no ſuch certain Anſwers as theſe can be given me, then I muſt beg Pardon, to tell your Lordſhips, that it cannot be denied, but that my Impriſonment is Indefinite, and if it be ſo, I do as an <hi>Engliſh</hi> Man affirm, that no Law in <hi>England</hi> can ſupport it.</p>
            <p>For the ſaying that if the King ſhould Adjourn this Court from time to time, the Party could not be Bailed till ſuch time as this Court ſhould ſit again; My Lord, If this ſhould be admitted as a reaſonable ſuppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſition (which under favour, I do not think your Lordſhip your ſelf does take it to be) yet it is but an Adjournment that is objected, and if the Parliament were but under an Adjournment, I would not have troubled your Lordſhip: But this is not the Caſe, for though ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times the King may Adjourn this or any other Court of <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> by reaſon of ſome extraordinary occaſion, as in Caſe of a Peſtilence or ſomething of that nature, (and I know there have been Preſidents of it) yet my Lord, theſe are upon Extreordinary occaſions, and it is not to be thought, nay I am very certain, that his Majeſty will never do any thing that ſhall deprive his Subjects of any of thoſe Rights the Law allows them; So that in one Caſe the Law obliges that the Termes ſhould be kept four times a Year, and that then the Court ſhall ſit if there be not extraordinary occaſions to hinder it; But in the other Caſe of a Parliament, the King lies under no oblihation, nor reſtraint, when he ſhall call or whether he will call it; and therefore the Inequality of the compariſon is ſufficiently apparent: And beſides this, It is as un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>known how long a Parliament ſhall ſit, as when it is to ſit; Inſomuch that I take all this, But to have offered additional Arguments on my ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>de &amp; ſhews how little the Arguments are that can be brought againſt me; &amp; I think it makes out to me and to all Engliſh men, that no man ought
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:63948:4"/>to lye under ſuch an Indefinite reſtraint as I do: and truly my Lord, I thought I ſhewed more reſpect to the Court, in giving a more General anſwer to this Objection (as I did before) then I can do now by being ſo particular.</p>
            <p>For the ſecond Objection, <hi>viz.</hi> That I am not Indefinitely impriſoned, for that when the King will pleaſe to call a Parliament, I would have a remedy there, and therefore I muſt wait till the King will call a Parli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ament.</p>
            <p>Truly my Lord, perhaps your Lordſhip may know the mind of the King or his Miniſters better than I do; But if you do not, I am ſure no man but the King can tell whether I ſhall have remedy then or no; for by the experience of three Parliaments that have been called ſince I was a Priſoner, it hath appeared that I have had no Remedy: There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I ſhould be very glad to ſee this matter any better proved, then it hath been that I am not Indefinitely Impriſoned; but if this cannot be proved neither, but that I muſt wait till the King ſhall pleaſe to call a Parliament; and when he ſhall call a Parliament, I ſhall be no more certain of my Remedy, than hitherto I have been, truly then I ſhall need no other Council but your Lordſhip to prove, I am under an Inde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>finite Impriſonment; and that any man in <hi>England</hi> may be ſo when the King pleaſes; and how any Doctrine can be more Arbitrary then that, or leſs to be deſended by Law, when ever that matter ſhall be brought into queſtion; Others then either your Lordſhip or I muſt be Judges, and thoſe who will be parties ſo much concerned in this queſtion for their own ſakes, as well as the publick, that I believe there is ſmall doubt to be made how they will then decide this queſtion.</p>
            <p>My Lord, If it ſhould then be found that this would hold water, and ſhould be maintained for good Doctrine; truly I think there would need no other Arbitrary power to be ſet up to make men quit this Country; For as to any mans Liberty, it might be equal to him whether he lived under the French Government, or under the Grand Signiors Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, as under a Government ſo Arbitrary as this Doctrine alone would make ours; And therefore I make no doubt my Lord, but that you will be very careful how you give it us for Law.</p>
            <p>As I ſhould be very ſorry that there ſhould be any ſuch Arbitrary Doctrine taught to ſet the Kings Prerogative higher or greater than it ought to be by Law, or then this King deſires, ſo I ſhould be as ſorry that the King ſhould not have that right which duly belongs to him, which is a Right and Power at all times to adminiſter Juſtice to his Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects, and which I never heard denied to the Kings of <hi>England,</hi> nor I hope I never ſhall: And my Lord I muſt ſay that the preſervation of that Right to the King, would take away all pretences for any of theſe dangerous and new Doctrines, for if the King may adminiſter Juſtice at all times to his Subjects, (as it hath been the care of Parliaments, and by <hi>Magna Charta</hi> it ſelf that he ſhould) there is no reaſon left for any of thoſe things to be ſtarted or put upon us.</p>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:63948:4"/>
            <p>'Tis true indeed, that the King cannot make Laws without a Parli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, but I did never hear in my whole Life, but that he could admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter Juſtice without his Parliament; and if he could not, his Subjects would be in a miſerable Condition; for ſurely it would be a very hard Caſe, if his Subjects could have no hopes of being righted by their So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veraigns Authority, either by himſelf, or in his Courts, in all Caſes, and at all times.</p>
            <p>The Houſe of Peers in Parliament ('tis true) is his greateſt Court, but they Sit only by Vertue of the King's Writ, and if the King ſhould dye (which I hope I ſhall never live to ſee) they would not then be a Court of Juſtice, nor any Court at all; and therefore, my Lord, in this Queſtion, the Royal Authority, and the Subjects Liberties are ſo involv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, that what Judgment ſoever ſhall be given, muſt paſs upon the one, as well as upon the other, and cannot poſſibly be divided.</p>
            <p>The third Objection that was made, is, That this Cauſe of mine is depending in Parliament, which is a Superior Court to this; and that the Supream Court having laid its hands upon me, therefore this Court can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not intermeddle.</p>
            <p>My Lord, There is no man living, that hath a greater Reverence for that Supreme Court, than I have, or that will go further than I will, to defend it, in all the Rights and Priviledges that belong to it by Law; Nay, my Lord, I have ſo much a greater Eſteem for that Court, becauſe I am ſure it will neither ſuffer me, nor any man living, to go unpuniſh'd, that ſhall tranſgreſs the Law, or that ſhall go about any way to make them Tranſgreſſors of the Law, or to make them ſuch as would be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrainers of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Liberties, beyond what the Law permits. They have ſhewed the contrary, when it was offered to them by a Bill from the Houſe of Commons, that they would have no ſuch abſolute Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity put into their hands over the Liberties of the Subject, but did then refuſe it; ſo that to ſay, that Supreme Court hath laid its hands upon any mans Liberty in <hi>England,</hi> further than the Law permits, would be to put an unjuſt Odium upon the Houſe of Lords to the Nation, inſtead of do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing them right; and therefore I muſt needs ſay, that in this particular Caſe of my own, I find only the word and name of Superior Court to be made uſe of againſt me, but nothing in reality; juſt as they were plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed in the Houſe of Commons to uſe the word Traiterouſly, in the Arti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles againſt me, when there was not a tittle of Treaſon in them, only that by calling it Treaſon, it might ſerve to lay me where I am.</p>
            <p>But, my Lord, I know no Court that is ſuperior at this time to this Court where I am now, and how any thing can be ſaid to be depending in a Court that hath no Being, I think will not very eaſily be defended from nonſence, without having the Matter extreamly well explained; and whenever that Superior Court ſhall have a Being, my Cauſe will then be before it, by my being Bailed to appear there. And for ſaying, it has laid its hand upon this Caſe of mine, it ought to be ſhewn in what
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:63948:5"/>the Superior Court hath laid its hand upon me, ſo as to keep me from Bail, when neither that Superior Court it ſelf (though it were willing ſo to do) is able to give me any Relief, nor that I can get to be Tryed or Diſcharged elſewhere, nor have any time prefixed when that Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perior Court ſhall Sit; as if there were no Juſtice left in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But if it be ſo, that I ſhall neither be Bailed, nor have it ſhewed, what hand the Superior Court has laid upon me to hinder it, then truly any man may be ſo concluded, and the Argument may be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cided, by the will and pleaſure of thoſe who have men in their Power; but the ſhadows of things, when there is no ſubſtance in the Argument, will not ſatisfie reaſonable men for an Anſwer, why ſo pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick a Grievance ſhall not be remedied; and I am confident, that the Superior Court it ſelf, will never ſuffer its Name to be made uſe of, nor themſelves to be made Properties, to ſupport ſuch a Grievance as may concern not only themſelves, but the whole Nation, both in this Age, and to all our Poſterities; and by which not only <hi>Magna Charta,</hi> and the Petition of Right, would be evaded, but the late Act of <hi>Habeas Corpus</hi> may alſo be eluded by this device; and the Parli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ament (when it ſhall meet again) will find, that inſtead of ſecuring their Liberties, they have only been hedging in the Cuckow; for that there is now a new way found out, by which all Acts for our Liberties may be made of no effect: And this cannot be contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicted, unleſs (as ſome would fancy) the King could not Impeach as well as the Commons; but there are ſo many Evidences to the contrary of that, as there is no room left for the Diſpute: And amongſt the Preſidents of that kind, there is one (becauſe it hath a double Conſequence) that I do deſire to put your Lordſhip in mind of.</p>
            <p>It is in the 5<hi rend="sup">o</hi>. <hi>H.</hi> 4th. in the Records of the Tower. There you will find, that the Commons came to Petition the King, that his Majeſty would be pleaſed, not to Impeach the Arch-Biſhop of <hi>Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terbury,</hi> the Earl of <hi>Northumberland,</hi> and ſome others, that were at that time accuſed for being in the Confederacy of Sir <hi>Henry Piercy,</hi> and the King grants their Requeſt, and does agree he would not Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peach them.</p>
            <p>I have quoted this the rather, becauſe of the double Preſident that is in this Caſe; for again the ſame day the Commons came (after his Majeſty had granted their former requeſt) and did fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Petition his Majeſty, that he would be pleaſed to affirm thoſe Lords (whom he had promiſed he would not Impeach) to be his true Liege-men; and the King did grant that alſo, by which it was then taken for granted, that he had ſet them <hi>Recti in Curia,</hi> (even though they were in that Conſpiracy with Sir <hi>Henry Piercy</hi>) and, my Lord, I give you this Inſtance, that you may obſerve two things by it: Firſt, That the Commons did Petition the King not to Impeach; and when he had granted that, it appears alſo, that by
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:63948:5"/>the King's declaring them to be his true Leige-men, it was by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons conceived, that the King did ſet them <hi>Recti in Curia;</hi> by which it does appear, what great regard the Houſe of Commons had to the King's bare Affirmation, of men being his true Liege-men; and <hi>I</hi> hope, that neither this King's Power nor Credit ſhall be leſs with his own Court, than that King's was with his Houſe of Commons; and <hi>I</hi> am ſure, no King's Affirmation can be greater, nor more publick, both to his Parliament and Kingdom, of any mans being a true Liege-man, (to uſe that old word) than the King's hath been concerning me.</p>
            <p>My Lord, there are ſome men, very unable to diſtinguiſh (though they would) between ſound and good ſence, and there are a great many, that are as willing to let men remain under their miſtakes; but ſince it weighs a great deal with ſome who do not very rightly diſtin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſh, it will be of abſolute neceſſity for me to explain-what it is, that is meant by a Caſe depending in Parliament, when there is no Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment: This will be beſt ſhewn by an Inſtance in a Writ of Error de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pending in Parliament, in which Caſe, when the Parliament is Sitting, and ſo the Writ is really and truly depending in the Court that is in Being; there can (during ſuch Sitting) be no Execution ſued upon the Judgment. But, my Lord, no ſooner is the Parliament diſſolved, but experience ſhews, that Execution may be ſued, and Goods levyed, and the properties of mens Eſtates changed; and therefore it is by this ſuffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciently plain, that depending is not then meant in the ſame ſence, or in the ſame manner, as it was meant when the Parliament was actually Sit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting; for then there could have been no Execution ſued.</p>
            <p>Now, my Lord, When a Parliament ſhall meet again, what does it meet with? It meets, it is true, with the ſame Cauſe again, (as to the Merits) but it meets it quite altered as to other Circumſtances, <hi>viz.</hi> as to the Execution that hath been granted by an inferior Court, in the inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>val of Parliament. And as to the change of property, for a man's Eſtate, (and perhaps of great value) may happen to be in another mans hands at the ſame time by the Execution; ſo that when a Parliament doth meet again, it doth meet, it is true, with the ſame Cauſe (as to the Merits) but indeed as to nothing elſe.</p>
            <p>And therefore, by this, it is clear, that a Parliament does only ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pect when it meets again, to meet with the Cauſe in the ſame ſtate (as to the Merits of the Cauſe) and doth not at all meddle or concern it ſelf to find fault with thoſe ſuppletory Acts that have been done by an in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferior Court in the interval, which was only to prevent failure of Juſtice, but it commends them for not having delayed Juſtice, and that men ſhould not be kept too long out of their Rights, (even though there may have been prodigious Wrong done to the Parties, if the Judgment have been erroneous) for that the Superior Court will at laſt ſee to the Error, if any have been committed by the Judgment of the inferior Court, and will enter upon all as entire again (as to its Merits) as if nothing had been done by the inferior Court; ſo that in reality, that which can only reconcile the ſence of being de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pending
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:63948:6"/>in Parliament, when the Parliament is diſſolved, is this laſt Order of the Houſe of Lords, which declares Impeachments, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to be continued, notwithſtanding Diſſolution. For by virtue of this laſt Order, the Lords do proceed upon the Cauſe, without be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning <hi>De novo,</hi> or having any new Writ or new Impeachment brought up to them: But this is new Doctrine, and never practiſed till of late; however, ſince they have done ſo, in this ſence, and in this only, a Cauſe may be ſaid to be depending; and ſo it was adjudged, in that ſingle inſtance of the Tryal and Condemnation of my Lord <hi>Stafford,</hi> but there they proceeded to the Merits of the Cauſe, and they tryed, condemned, my Lord <hi>Stafford;</hi> and there is no manner of doubt, but by virtue of their late Order, they may proceed upon me when they ſhall meet, as they ſhall think fit, notwithſtanding my having been bailed; for I deſire not to have the Merits of my Cauſe removed from before the Lords, if I might, but that they may do with me as they pleaſe, even to Condem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation, if they ſhall have Cauſe, which <hi>I</hi> hope in God they never ſhall.</p>
            <p>Therefore, <hi>I</hi> ſay, my Lord, in this ſence only which <hi>I</hi> have ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plained, a Cauſe may be ſaid to be depending, though a Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment is not in being; but <hi>I</hi> will challenge the ableſt Lawyer, with all the Sophiſtry he can uſe, together with his Law, to ſhew me how he can poſſibly diſtinguiſh the Caſe of Writs of Error, from the Caſe of Impeachment, or wherein they differ, as to their depending, in the Intervals of Parliament; and I likewiſe challenge him to make appear, how Bail is any other than ſuch a ſuppletory Act, to relieve a man from being kept too long from his Liberty, as the granting of Execution in the Interval, is to relieve a man from being too long kept out of his Money or Eſtate, for that the Merits of the Cauſe both in the one Caſe and the other, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mains entire for the Parliament to recommit upon (if they ſee cauſe) as well as to reverſe the Judgment, and all the Proceedings, upon the Writ of Error.</p>
            <p>Where is then the difference, my Lord? if there be any difference, <hi>I</hi> think it lies only in this, that in one Caſe there may be an erroneous Judgment, and a man may be almoſt undone and ruined, by being wrongfully diſpoſſeſs'd of his Eſtate (be it never ſo great) but in this Caſe, the ſuppletory Act which is done to admit to bail, can only be to eaſe a man from his too long or perhaps perpetual impriſonment, and can hurt no body, nor take no mans liberty from him, to grant him his; but yet this muſt be thought an hard Caſe, and the other a very eaſie one, and fit to be practiſed every day.</p>
            <p>My Lord, if the Law has taken care, and made ſuch proviſion, that a man ſhall not be kept too long out of 10 <hi>l.</hi> in money, or out of 40.<hi>l.</hi> a year in Land, then it would be ſtrange, that the Law ſhould not have made proviſion, that a man ſhould not be kept too long out of his Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty, and when there is no proſpect of his having it.</p>
            <pb n="11" facs="tcp:63948:6"/>
            <p>Beſides, in a Writ of Errour the Judgment given is controverted, and the power of awarding Execution is ſuſpended upon that very accompt, becauſe the Judgment of the Court is in queſtion, and the Juſtice of it is brought in diſpute, whether they have judged right or wrong.</p>
            <p>Now, My Lord, if the diſſolution of a Parliament can reſtore the Judges power in the interval of Parliament, ſo as to award an Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion upon a Man's Eſtate, where the property ſhall be changed and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tered, and notwithſtanding their Juſtice was brought in queſtion, and that they may have done great wrong to the Party by their judgment, and yet we are to believe, that the ſame Diſſolution cannot reſtore the power of the Judges ſo as to give a Man a little Eaſe from a Confinement within four Walls, where the Juſtice of no Court is queſtioned nor ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raigned, nor no wrong can have been done to any body; But on the contrary, does right to the King, who by his conſent ſhews his Will to have a Man bailed; and great right to the Subject, who ought to be delivered from the danger of an indefinite Impriſonment which is ſo contrary to Law: Then indeed there muſt be ſome Infallibility ſuppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed in that Chair, which ſhall maintain ſuch Doctrine, and muſt be ſubmitted to, with the ſame Implicite Faith, which they do who can believe Infallibility.</p>
            <p>But for my part (who can believe Inſallibily in no kind upon Earth) I confeſs I muſt have my Reaſon better ſatisfied, before I can any more believe this Expoſition of the Law, than I can believe thoſe infallible Mens Expoſitions of the Goſpel.</p>
            <p>My Lord, I hope I have made plain to your Lordſhip, what it is that is meant, or can be underſtood by a Cauſe depending in Parliament when there is none, and how and in what ſenſe onely it can be under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtood to be ſo depending; and it is as plain, that the bailing of me is no intermedling with the merits of the Cauſe in Parliament, but on the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, an evident affirmation of the jurisdiction of that ſupreme Court; and if I cannot be admitted to bail in ſome other Court than the Houſe of Lords, it is contrary to what my Warrant of Commitment im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plies, by which I am committed onely till I am diſcharged by due courſe of Law, for which I am properly in this place.</p>
            <p>My Lord, it cannot be meant that Bail can be any more than a Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pletory Act <hi>(propter rei neceſſitatem)</hi> and for the eaſe of the Subject, and it is impoſſible for that old Rule, of <hi>Salus populi Suprema Lex eſto,</hi> to be more aptly applied in any caſe in the World than in this, that concerns every Man in <hi>England</hi> in his Liberty: For ſhould it be other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, Pray ſee what the conſequence of this Doctrine would be, that becauſe a ſuperiour Court which is not now in being (nor hath it in its own power to be ſo) hath committed a Man, therefore he cannot be admitted to Bail; what ſhould become of Men, if after the diſſolution of a Parliament, there can be no poſſibility of having juſtice done them?</p>
            <pb n="12" facs="tcp:63948:7"/>
            <p>Nay farther, if it ſhould be granted that this Court cannot inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meddle, becauſe the Superiour Court has committed, by that Doctrine it would not matter whether the Commitment were for Treaſon, or for the ſmalleſt quarrel or miſdemeanor, for which a Man might happen to be in Priſon at the time of a diſſolution of a Parliament; nor would it be any matter, whether the Order of the Houſe of Lords were revo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked or not.</p>
            <p>For it is an Order of a Superiour Court, which will ſtill be a Supe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riour Court though the Order were burnt, and yet that muſt be enough to keep one in Priſon by this Rule, for that there would ſtill be no other remedy though the Order were repealed.</p>
            <p>But, My Lord, the Warrant of Commitment ſhews the Lords Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rections to be contrary to this Opinion, for I can ſhew ſeveral Inſtances of Warrants which run, ſome to be kept <hi>till further order of that Houſe,</hi> others to be kept <hi>till they ſhall be diſcharged by the Houſe,</hi> and others to be kept <hi>till the pleaſure of the Houſe be further ſignified,</hi> and others <hi>during the pleaſure of that Houſe;</hi> But my Warrant is, <hi>till I am diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged by due courſe of Law:</hi> Now I doubt not, but if the Lords had thought thoſe words had not given a latitude for relief elſewhere, they would have worded the Warrant otherwiſe, and inſtead of ſaying <hi>by due courſe of Law,</hi> would have ſaid, <hi>till I were diſcharged by that Houſe,</hi> if the Lords had thought there had been no other remedy by Law, but by that Houſe. But, My Lord, the Lords will not act any thing above the Law, they will keep every thing within the compaſs of the Law; and I am ſure that there cannot be a better Example to fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low, than the Example of thoſe wiſe and great Men of that great Court, and I deſire it may be followed and not contradicted.</p>
            <p>For by this Doctrine, truly, My Lord, Liberty it ſelf would not only be utterly loſt; but to make the Riddle the greater, and the manner more ridiculous, it would be loſt, and yet no body invade it: For the <hi>King</hi> he conſents to my Bail (if he hath any power) ſo he does not intend to deprive me of my Liberty; The Lords would for their own ſakes and Juſtice ſake (if it were in their power to meet, and have time to ſit ſo long as to take the Caſe of a ſingle Perſon into conſideration) do me juſtice, either in diſcharging or trying me; So that in my Caſe, here is a Subject of <hi>England</hi> impriſoned by no body, and yet no Power up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Earth can relieve me; Shew me an example of this in any Nation un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Sun, but this, that there wants a power in the Government to relieve a Priſoner at all times (if it would) and I will be ſatisfied; Nay, My Lord, the very <hi>Spaniſh Inquiſition</hi> is more reaſonable than this, for though the Cauſe may be unjuſt that they commit a Man for, and their uſage of him may be very ſevere while he is there, yet the <hi>Inqui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitors</hi> (if they pleaſe) <hi>can</hi> deliver him; there is no Priſoner in the World but <hi>can</hi> be delivered by ſome power or other, but me; and, My Lord, this is a Rule that muſt be for every Man in <hi>England</hi> as well as me, and I am not ſo inconſiderable but that my fate may be made a Preſident of note.</p>
            <pb n="13" facs="tcp:63948:7"/>
            <p>The Opinions, My Lord, that were given by the Judges in the Caſe of Ship-money, appear far more tolerable in my Opinion than this; for I know there is no Man but had rather have a Sentence paſs't againſt his Eſtate (which he may recover again) than have it paſſed againſt his Liberty, which he may never have, and which is more valuable than any Eſtate.</p>
            <p>Beſides, where is the Juſtice of the Nation? and what a ſhame would it be to our Laws and to our Government; that it could be ſaid of this Countrey, that a Man might be puniſhed by Impriſonment in <hi>England</hi> (where the Government is not Arbitrary) for ſeven Years or more, and at laſt be found guilty of no Offence? and what ſatisfaction could be in nature given to that Man? I ſay if that Man could have a Crown given him, it could not make him ſatisfaction for the loſs of his Liberty all his life, which may be the Conſequence of this Doctrine; and, my Lord, there are Precedents good ſtore where Men have ſuffered ſufficiently for their Judgments againſt the <hi>Liberty and Property of the Subject,</hi> but I never found one that ſuffered in the Defence either of the one or the other.</p>
            <p>I have ſhewn I think ſufficiently what can be meant either in my Caſe or any other, by a Cauſe depending in <hi>Parliament,</hi> when there is no <hi>Parliament,</hi> as alſo how much Inferiour Courts do meddle with things of much an higher nature than Bail will be; Inſomuch that truly I ſhould think it might be ſufficient to ſay no more than I have ſaid; But I do not know what may be ſufficient in my Caſe; and therefore, my Lord, you muſt Pardon me, if I do put you in mind of a Caſe wherein you have gone to the merits of the Cauſe it ſelf when De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pending in <hi>Parliament.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>It is <hi>Fitz-Harris</hi> his Caſe; and I know very well what Anſwers will be given me; as that <hi>that</hi> was a Caſe rejected by the Lords, and that it was not the ſame Treaſon for which he was Impeached, and other things that I could mention; but I know your Lordſhip will ſpeak by the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord of the Court (of which I have here a Copy) and the Record is that which muſt ſatisfie the World an hundred years hence, by which it will appear to them, that he was Impeached, and Tryed, and Condem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, depending that Impeachment; for he made that his <hi>Plea,</hi> and Mr. Attorney General demurring to it, the Court muſt take the matter pleaded, as confeſſed and allow'd; and this being ſo, I ſhould think there ſhould be no ſcruple made in the point of Bail, or if there ſhould, there muſt certainly be very great hardſhip in one caſe or the other, and muſt be very diſſicult to be anſwered.</p>
            <p>But to Conclude, beſides all this, I am the King's Priſoner; and I have the <hi>King</hi>'s Pardon, and if I cannot get to be <hi>Bailed,</hi> there is not only a defect of Juriſdiction in this Court, but a defect of the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gal Authority and Power of the Kings of <hi>England</hi> to adminiſter Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:63948:8"/>to their Subjects; which was never heard of I think, and I hope I ſhall never live to hear of it (Eſpecially from the <hi>King</hi>'s Supreme Ordinary Court of Juſtice.) And that, My Lord, that muſt make this Caſe the more unhappy at this time is, that we live in days wherein his Majeſty's Prerogatives are ſo much brought in queſtion: For what Prerogative hath He which is more undoubted than his power of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doning? and yet you ſee that brought in queſtion to the utmoſt, and thoſe that are the ableſt Men that ſpeak againſt that power, do laugh at the little ſmall Triflers who object, that the <hi>King</hi> may Pardon before Impeachment, and after the Sentence be given, but not betwixt thoſe times; They laugh at this, and tell you that he cannot Pardon at all, and it is eaſily perceived that if they could reach their deſign, they would have it underſtood, That <hi>Treaſon</hi> may be committed againſt the People, and by that Doctrine another High Court of Juſtice, may be ſet up, and the <hi>King</hi> may be tried by his People as well as he can try them; My Lord, there are a great many of Conſequences attending up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on that Doctrine, which I am ſure will ne'er be countenanced by the <hi>King</hi>'s Courts; but I ſhall not wonder that ſuch Men as theſe be try<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing their Projects, and think themſelves in the Right to do ſo, If they find his Majeſty cannot doe ſo much as a leſſer Act of Grace for his Priſoner, which is but to give him eaſe from too long or perhaps a per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petual Impriſonment; for if he hath not power ſo much as to Bail his own Priſoner, I ſhall not wonder if others queſtion whether he hath power to Pardon him.</p>
            <p>My Lord, I have ſeen ſuch Keepers of our Liberties, from whom I ſhould expect ſuch Doctrines, but I thank God that by our Laws the <hi>King</hi> is the Keeper of our Liberties, and therefore I hope I ſhall not hear any ſuch Doctrine by which he can only be the Keeper of us in Priſons, but ſhall have no more power than another Man, to ſet his Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoner at liberty, although his Will be only to give his Priſoner Eaſe (as the Law intends) againſt Indefinite Impriſonment.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Laſtly,</hi> My Lord, If I ſhould die in Priſon with this Pardon by me, which I have ſhew'd Your Lordſhip; or ſuppoſe that the Houſe of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons (if it were but with a deſign to deſtroy the Pardon) would give ſome other reaſon than the Pardon (as being better ſatisfied con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning me, or any thing elſe) why they would proſecute me no more (of which there be divers Precedents). What a Wound would thereby be given to the <hi>King</hi>'s Prerogative? and pray how is it poſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble almoſt to give it a greater blow than this would be?</p>
            <p>What a Precedent would it be to Poſterity to ſay, that a Man had lain Three, four or five years or more in Priſon notwithſtanding a Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don, that ſignified nothing all that time? for that the <hi>King</hi> would have Eaſed him if he could, and hath ſhewed his Court that he would do ſo, but was not able ſo much as to have him Bailed? would not this put that Prerogative in great hazard? I confeſs I do wonder that ſome others beſides Your Lordſhip have not taken more care of the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rogative of the <hi>King,</hi> for their own Sakes as well as the <hi>King</hi>'s; For it
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:63948:8"/>would be very convenient it ſhould be uſefull, if ever it ſhould be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come neceſſary; And it is not improbable, but if the <hi>King</hi> ſhould here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after find ſuch a Prerogative diminiſh'd, he would not only reflect up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on his Loſs, but upon thoſe who might have adviſed better, or might have better defended this Prerogative of the <hi>King;</hi> And for the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects Liberties, there will never be Eyes wanting to inquire after any invaſion which ſhall be made of that kind.</p>
            <p>Upon the whole, I have troubled Your Lordſhip too long, but it hath been upon a Subject of the greateſt Concern to <hi>Engliſh-men:</hi> I have ſuch Bail to offer to Your Lordſhip, as I am ſure cannot be denyed, and I am in my own Conſcience ſufficiently ſatisfied, that I am detain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed a Priſoner from Bail, neither by the <hi>King,</hi> by the Lords, nor by the Laws; and therefore, my Lord, I do humbly pray your Lordſhip you would pleaſe to accept my Bail, and as I here offer your Lordſhip my Pardon again, ſo I again pray the benefit of it, and I deſire your Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip it may be read in Court.</p>
            <p>THE Lord Chief Juſtice then ſpoke, and ſo did all the reſt of the Judges, (upon the Earls deſiring that they would ſeveral<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly deliver their Opinions) And the Lord Chief Juſtice, and Mr. Juſtice <hi>Dolbin,</hi> did deliver their opinions, that the Earl could not be relieved by that Court. Mr. Juſtice <hi>Jones</hi> concluded his Diſcourſe with ſaying, that he could not give his Judgment that the Earl ſhould be Bailed AT THAT TIME. Mr. Juſtice <hi>Raymond</hi> did ſay, he could not ſee but that there would be a <hi>failure of Juſtice</hi> if ſo be his Lordſhip ſhould not have Liberty upon Bail; but that he had not had time to view Precedents, and therefore it would be very unfit for him at preſent to be poſitive in what he did ſay.</p>
            <p>And then the Lord Chief Juſtice did tell the Earl, he muſt be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tented to be Remanded.</p>
            <p>I Have not dared to ſet down the Particulars of what was ſpoken by the Judges, the Writer not having well heard what was ſaid by ſome of them, but ſome are ſaid to have taken Exact Notes, which may perhaps be Publiſhed hereafter by themſelves: And it is likewiſe reported that the Earl (not having been permitted to reply in Court to the Reaſons gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven by the Judges againſt his Lordſhip's being Bailed) does likewiſe in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to put forth his Anſwer to the Reaſons which were then Objected againſt him.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
